He distanced himself from love as he distanced himself from pain, until
one woman got close enough to open his heart to the world.
Shadowlands is a drama, romance film directed by Richard Attenborough.
Lewis, a world-renowned writer and professor, leads a passionless
life until he meets spirited poet Joy Gresham.
C. S. 'Jack' Lewis, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Joy Gresham, played by Debra Winger.
Warnie Lewis, played by Edward Hardwicke.
Christopher Riley, played by John Wood.
Harry Harrington, played by Michael Denison.
Dr Craig, played by Peter Firth.
Shadowlands is a 1993 British biographical drama film
about the relationship between academic C.
Lewis (played by Anthony Hopkins) and Jewish American poet Joy Davidman (played by Debra
Winger), her death from cancer, and how this challenged his Christianity.
It is loosely based on Lewis's own account in his book A Grief Observed.
The film was directed by Richard Attenborough with a screenplay by William
Nicholson based on his 1985 television film and 1989 stage play.
The 1985 script began life as I Call It Joy written for Thames
Television by Brian Sibley and Norman Stone.
Sibley later wrote the book Shadowlands: The True Story of C.
Lewis and Joy Davidman.
The film won the 1993 BAFTA Award for Outstanding British Film.
The film marked the last film appearance of English actor Michael Denison.
The film explores themes of stroke of fate, england,
brother, christianity, literature.
The tone is emotional.